A Guide to the William Byrd Community House Archives, 1946-1986
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
William Byrd Community House Archives, 1946-1986
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 259
27.98 linear feet
William Byrd Community House
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
The collection was a donation to the department authorized by the Board of Directors of the William Byrd Community House in January 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
According to the William Byrd Community House 1975 Annual Report, "the idea of the organization was conceived early in this century when a small group of nurses, ministering to the sick on Oregon Hill, observed increasing symptoms of poverty. In an effort to help these people find new meaning for their lives, they organized clubs and classes offering recreational and educational facilities. In 1923 the WBCH, operating under a new charter of incorporation, was organized to carry on these programs. After its incorporation, the WBCH became a charter member of the National Federation of Settlements. The agency has been housed at four different locations. Since 1947 the WBCH has been housed in the Arent's Free Library, the first free library in Richmond, located at 224 South Cherry Street. One wing of the building continues to serve as a library for the neighborhood.
"Several civic organizations have played an invaluable part in our history by providing support and encouragement. The Richmond Kiwanis club helped to equip our building and playground. They so completely outfitted our playground that it was designated as the 'Kiwanis Playground.' The Cosmopolitan Club completely equipped our dental clinic and have for nearly twenty-five years continued to support this program. In 1968 the Rotary Boys Club, operating in the neighborhood since 1948, merged with WBCH. The Richmond Rotary Club phased out their support over a four year period. Many other clubs and organizations throughout the city have sent us both volunteers and material gifts over the years. At the present time, the WBCH is comprised of three integral parts: Community House activities and WBCH Field and Gymnasium, both funded by the United Way of Greater Richmond, and Arent's Free Public Library whose operating costs are paid by the St. Andrew's Association, Trustees of Miss Arent's Estate.
"The area served by the WBCH is bounded by the James River on the south, Belvidere Street on the east, Main Street on the north and Randolph Street on the west. The agency's total service area included approximately 4,400 residents."
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the history, camps, committees and programs, the Oregon Hill Project, reports and budgets of the William Byrd Community House. There are also a small number of slides that show the houses involved in the housing projects of Oregon Hill and other programs.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by series and chronologically therein.
Organization
Series I--General Files 1959-1986
Series II--Constitution and By-Laws 1960-1977
Series III--Camps 1961-1968
Series IV--Committees and Programs 1959-1981
Series V--Oregon Hill Project 1954-1979
Series VI--Correspondence 1969-1983
Series VII-Reports 1946-1984
Series VIII--Budgets 1949-1981
Series IX--Slides of Housing Projects
Contents List
- General Files 1959-1986
  - A Byrd's Eye View Newsletter 1979-1981 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - A Community Profile (Box-folder 1.2)
  - A Community's Image of a Neighborhood Center 1975 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Adult Aid and Care 1982 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Adult Worker Information (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Advisory Board (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Advisory Council 1978-1980 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Annual Salute to Volunteers (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Appraisal-Office Building in Henrico County 1972 (Box-folder 1.9)
  - A Study of the Recreation Agencies in Metropolitan Richmond 1965 (Box-folder 1.10)
  - Attendance 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Audio Equipment 1977 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - Audit 1974 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Articles of Incorporation 1970 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - Awards Night 1969 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Awards Night 1970 (Box-folder 1.16)
  - Awards Night 1971 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - AWARE Brochures-Scattered Volumes (Box-folder 1.18)
  - Baccalaureate Social Work Field Mannual 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Bank Book and Deposit Slips 1973 (Box-folder 1.20)
  - Better Community Development Act 1974 (Box-folder 1.21)
  - Big Sister 1971 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Big Sister Nursery 1968 (Box-folder 1.23)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield 1975 (Box-folder 1.24)
  - Board and Staff Meetings 1971-1977 (Box-folder 1.25)
  - Board Member Information 1977 (Box-folder 1.26)
  - Board of Governors (Box-folder 1.27)
  - Board of Governors 1965-1968 (Box-folder 1.28)
  - Board of Governors 1979-1980 (Box-folder 1.29)
  - Board of Governors 1981 (Box-folder 1.30)
  - Board of Governors 1982 (Box-folder 1.31)
  - Board of Governors 1983 (Box-folder 1.32)
  - Board of Governors-Minutes 1976-1980 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Boy Scouts of America 1976 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Bus Accident 1973 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Business Policies and Rules 1975 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Casework Unit Resources (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Census, Voter Registration, Health and Crime (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Ceramics Classes (Box-folder 2.7)
  - CETA Requisitions (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Child Abuse and Neglect 1975 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Child Care Aid 1980-1981 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Child Development-Parent Education Advising Board 1981 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Christmas 1970 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Christmas Help 1976 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - Christmas Pageant 1968 (Box-folder 2.14)
  - Christmas Parties 1966 (Box-folder 2.15)
  - Citizen's Community Study of the Metropolitan Area 1974 (Box-folder 2.16)
  - Citizen's Study 1972 (Box-folder 2.17)
  - City Council Dockets 1978 (Box-folder 2.18)
  - Clippings of Youth Activities (Box-folder 2.19)
  - Community Graphics-VCU 1977 (Box-folder 2.20)
  - Community Improvement Maps 1977 (Box-folder 2.21)
  - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act-Grant 1980 (Box-folder 2.22)
  - Contracts Contract (Box-folder 2.23)
  - Contracts (1 of 2) 1977-1986 (Box-folder 2.24)
  - Contracts (2 of 2) 1977-1986 (Box-folder 2.25)
  - Cub Scouts 1979 (Box-folder 2.26)
  - Daily Log 1976 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Deinstitutionalization-Its Impact on Homes for Adults 1981 (Box-folder 2.28)
  - Delinquincy Prevention and Yourth Development-Grant Information 1977 (Box-folder 2.29)
  - Deliquincy Prevention and Youth Development-Proposal 1981 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - Dental Clinic 1967 (Box-folder 2.31)
  - Dental Clinic 1971 (Box-folder 2.32)
  - Department of Nursing (MCV) (Box-folder 2.33)
  - Department of Occupational Therapy (MCV) (Box-folder 2.34)
  - Director's Report 1974 (Box-folder 2.35)
  - Directors Report 1975 (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Drop-Out Advisory Board 1984 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - EDGE 1978-1979 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Employment Application Pre-Test (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Employment Information 1981 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Equipment-Directions, Guarentees, Etc. (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Executive Roundtable 1966 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Facts and Figures on Bainbridge and Blackwell 1979 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Family and Children's Services 1977 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Fan Tenants Union 1972 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Field Instructor's Workshop 1976 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Fieldwork and Volunteer Applications 1963-1968 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - Fieldwork Students 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3.12)
  - Film Script (Box-folder 3.13)
  - Flyers and Notices 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3.14)
  - Flyers/Invitations 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3.15)
  - Folk Fair 1976 (Box-folder 3.16)
  - Folk Fair 1977 (Box-folder 3.17)
  - Folk Fair 1978 (Box-folder 3.18)
  - Folk Fair 1979 (Box-folder 3.19)
  - Foundations of Education Class-VCU 1977 (Box-folder 3.20)
  - 4-H 1975 (Box-folder 3.21)
  - Friends Association (Box-folder 3.22)
  - Fund Raising 1973 (Box-folder 3.23)
  - Grace Arents Free library 1971 (Box-folder 3.24)
  - Grace Arents Library-Plan of Operation (Box-folder 3.25)
  - Grace Arents Neighborhood Study (Box-folder 3.26)
  - Grants 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3.27)
  - Group Activities 1965 (Box-folder 3.28)
  - Group Activities 1966 (Box-folder 3.29)
  - Group Activity Sheets 1968 (Box-folder 3.30)
  - Gymnastics (Box-folder 3.31)
  - Halloween 1970 (Box-folder 3.32)
  - Highland Park-Its Youth and Their Needs 1979 (Box-folder 3.33)
  - Home Improvement Applications 1973 (Box-folder 3.34)
  - HOMEWORK-Metro Housing Coalition 1973 (Box-folder 3.35)
  - House Activities 1967 (Box-folder 3.36)
  - House Equipment 1975 (Box-folder 3.37)
  - Housing 1976 (Box-folder 3.38)
  - Housing Code For Rental Dwellings and Units (Box-folder 3.39)
  - Housing Task Force 1977 (Box-folder 3.40)
  - Ice Breakers (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Information on the Teen and the Self (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Injuries 1976 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - In-Service Training 1978 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Insurance 1970 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Insurance 1975-1977 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Insurance Policies 1981 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - International Year of the Child Conference 1979 (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Interviews (Box-folder 4.9)
  - Inventory for Fire Insurance 1972 (Box-folder 4.10)
  - Invoices from Housing Construction Project (Box-folder 4.11)
  - Jewish Community Center (Box-folder 4.12)
  - Job Description (Youth Workers) 1972-1974 (Box-folder 4.14)
  - Jr. Board 1975-1976 (Box-folder 4.15)
  - Jr. League 1959-1962 (Box-folder 4.16)
  - J. Sargeant Reynolds 1976 (Box-folder 4.17)
  - J. Sargeant Reynolds-Volunteerism 1976 (Box-folder 4.18)
  - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration Grants 1979 (Box-folder 4.19)
  - Lease for Building (Box-folder 4.20)
  - Letters of Committment 1977-1979 (Box-folder 4.21)
  - Letters Soliciting Support-Resource/Budget Information 1973 (Box-folder 4.22)
  - Marketing Social Work in the Human Service Industry 1983 (Box-folder 4.23)
  - Master Plan of Land Use, Community Facilities and Trafficways 1964 (Box-folder 4.24)
  - Materials Devised by the Recreation Coordinator 1981 (Box-folder 4.25)
  - Membership Count 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4.26)
  - Metro Area Resource Clearing House 1978 (Box-folder 4.27)
  - Minutes 1966-1967 (Box-folder 4.28)
  - Minutes 1974 (Box-folder 4.29)
  - Minutes of Board of Governors 1972-1974 (Box-folder 4.30)
  - Minutes of Board of Governors 1975-1977 (Box-folder 4.31)
  - Minutes of Board of Governors 1981 (Box-folder 4.32)
  - Minutes of Board of Governors 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4.33)
  - Minutes of Board of Governors 1984-1985 (Box-folder 4.34)
  - Miscellaneous Guides to Home Improvement (1 of 2) (Box-folder 4.35)
  - Miscellaneous Guides to Home Improvement (2 of 2) (Box-folder 4.36)
  - Miscellaneous Legal Documents 1976 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Model Cities Group Work 1981 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Monthly Statistics 1980 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - National Federation of Settlements 1974-1976 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - National Federation of Settlements 1975 (Box-folder Box 5.5)
  - National Federation of Settlements and Neighborhood Centers 1978 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - National Federation of Settlements-Full Employment 1976 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - National Federation of Settlements-Legislative Conference 1976 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - National Health and Welfare Retirement Association 1963 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - Needs Assessment-East End 1982 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Newsletter (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Newsletters 1971 (Box-folder 5.12)
  - News Media-TV 1975 (Box-folder 5.13)
  - Nomination Proposals 1973 (Box-folder 5.14)
  - Nursery School PTA 1958-1959 (Box-folder 5.15)
  - Nursery School PTA 1959-1960 (Box-folder 5.16)
  - Nursery School PTA 1960-1961 (Box-folder 5.17)
  - Nursery School PTA 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5.18)
  - Nursery School PTA 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5.19)
  - Nursery School PTA 1963-1964 (Box-folder 5.20)
  - Nursery School PTA 1964-1965 (Box-folder 5.21)
  - Nursery School PTA 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5.22)
  - Opening Doors for Children-Brochure 1978-1982 (Box-folder 5.23)
  - Opportunities Industrialization Center 1977 (Box-folder 5.24)
  - Opportunities Industrialization Center 1978 (Box-folder 5.25)
  - Opportunities Industrialization Center-General (Box-folder 5.26)
  - Opportunities Industrialization Center-Orientation 1977 (Box-folder 5.27)
  - Orientation 1969 (Box-folder 5.28)
  - Orientation Folder 1973 (Box-folder 5.29)
  - Outreach 1981 (Box-folder 5.30)
  - Parent Group (Box-folder 5.31)
  - Perfect Allocations 1982 (Box-folder 5.32)
  - Personnel Policies 1961 (Box-folder 5.33)
  - Planning District Study 1979 (Box-folder 5.34)
  - Prevention Post Award Conference 1977 (Box-folder 5.35)
  - Program Director-Job Description 1976 (Box-folder 5.36)
  - Property Code 1972-1975 (Box-folder 5.37)
  - Public Relations Annual Meeting 1976 (Box-folder 5.38)
  - Public Service Employment-Grant 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.39)
  - Puppeteers 1963-1964 (Box-folder 5.40)
  - Purchases and Repairs 1971 (Box-folder 5.41)
  - Purpose 1975 (Box-folder 5.42)
  - Real Estate Tax Exemption 1970 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Recreational Therapy Department 1977 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Recreation-Contract (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Recreation in Metropolitan Richmond 1963 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Recreation Group Work-Executive Roundtable 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Recreation Group Work-Executive Roundtable 1965 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - Response to the Citizens Community Study 1975 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Retirement 1975 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Retirement Plan (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Richmond Area Manpower System 1981 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Richmond Area Manpower System-Recreation Project 1977-1978 (Box-folder 6.11)
  - Richmond Community Action Plan (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Richmond Metropolitan Authority-Expressway 1972 (Box-folder 6.13)
  - Richmond United Neighboors (1 of 2) (Box-folder 6.14)
  - Richmond United Neighboors (2 of 2) (Box-folder 6.15)
  - Richmond United Neighboors 1985 (Box-folder 6.16)
  - Robert E. Lee Council-Boy Scouts of America 1977 (Box-folder 6.17)
  - Scholarship Fund 1968-1970 (Box-folder 6.18)
  - Scholarship Information 1976 (Box-folder 6.19)
  - School of Social Work-Virginia Commonwealth University (Box-folder 6.20)
  - Self-Help Housing (1 of 2) 1976 (Box-folder 6.21)
  - Self-Help Housing (2 of 2) 1976 (Box-folder 6.22)
  - Senior Board 1972 (Box-folder 6.23)
  - Senior Board 1973 (Box-folder 6.24)
  - Senior Board Members 1973 (Box-folder 6.25)
  - Sex Education 1969 (Box-folder 6.26)
  - Sign-In Sheet for Salary 1975 (Box-folder 6.27)
  - Staff 1969 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Staff Agenda-Minutes 1973 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Staff Meetings 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Staff Meetings 1971-1972 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Staff Meetings 1972 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Staff Meetings 1974-1975 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - Staff Meetings 1975 (Box-folder 7.7)
  - Staff Meetings 1977 (Box-folder 7.8)
  - Staff Meetings 1978-1981 (Box-folder 7.9)
  - Staff Meetings 1979-1981 (Box-folder 7.10)
  - Staff Minutes 1963-1964 (Box-folder 7.11)
  - Staff Minutes 1965-1969 (Box-folder 7.12)
  - Staff Minutes 1972-1974 (Box-folder 7.13)
  - Staff Minutes 1977 (Box-folder 7.14)
  - Staff Work Schedules 1973-1975 (Box-folder 7.15)
  - Statement of Purpose 1969-1971 (Box-folder 7.16)
  - Students and Volunteer Orientation (Box-folder 7.17)
  - Summary of the Housing and Community Development Act 1974 (Box-folder 7.18)
  - Summer Admission 1971 (Box-folder 7.19)
  - Summer Employment 1976 (Box-folder 7.20)
  - Summer Employment 1977 (Box-folder 7.21)
  - Summer Orientation 1976 (Box-folder 7.22)
  - Teen Activities 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7.23)
  - Teen Talent Show (Box-folder 7.24)
  - Tenant Organizing 1973 (Box-folder 7.25)
  - Time Sheets 1975 (Box-folder 7.26)
  - Time Sheets 1976 (Box-folder 7.27)
  - Time Sheets for Fieldwork Students 1963-1964 (Box-folder 7.28)
  - Time Sheets for Volunteers 1963-1965 (Box-folder 7.29)
  - Time Sheets for Volunteers 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7.30)
  - Title III 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7.31)
  - Title III Grant 1977-1980 (Box-folder 7.32)
  - Title III Proposal 1980-1981 (Box-folder 7.33)
  - Title III Proposal 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Title III Proposal 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Tool Inventory 1973 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Transportation and De-Leading (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Transportation and De-Leading Contract (Box-folder 8.5)
  - United Givers Fund 1974-1976 (Box-folder 8.6)
  - United Neighborhood Centers of America-Proposal 1981 (Box-folder 8.9)
  - United Neighborhood Centers of America-Proposal Material (Box-folder 8.10)
  - United States Department of Agriculture 1978 (Box-folder 8.11)
  - United States Department of Agriculture 1980-1981 (Box-folder 8.12)
  - United Way 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8.13)
  - United Way 1982 (Box-folder 8.14)
  - United Way-Agency Relations Manual 1972 (Box-folder 8.15)
  - United Way Survey 1978 (Box-folder 8.16)
  - Urban Dynamics-Citizen Education, Awareness and Participation Workshop 1970 (Box-folder 8.17)
  - Virginia Employment Commission 1975 (Box-folder 8.18)
  - Virginia Outdoor Commission 1965 (Box-folder 8.19)
  - Virginia Volunteer Conference 1981 (Box-folder 8.20)
  - Vista Information 1973 (Box-folder 8.21)
  - Volunteer and Student Leader Applications 1965-1967 (Box-folder 8.22)
  - Volunteer Applications 1961-1963 (Box-folder 8.23)
  - Volunteer Applications 1968 (Box-folder 8.24)
  - Volunteer Emergency Foster Care of Virginia (1 of 3) 1980 (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Volunteer Emergency Foster Care of Virginia (2 of 3) 1980 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Volunteer Emergency Foster Care of Virginia (3 of 3) 1980 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Volunteer Needs 1973 (Box-folder 9.4)
  - Volunteer Orientation 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9.5)
  - Volunteer Service Bureau (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Volunteer Service Bureau 1962-1963 (Box-folder 9.7)
  - Volunteer Service Bureau 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9.8)
  - West End Advisory Council 1972-1974 (Box-folder 9.9)
  - Youth Engaged in Sports-CETA Grant (Box-folder 9.10)
  - Youth Employment 1981 (Box-folder 9.11)
  - Youth Employment Grants (Box-folder 9.12)
  - Youth Department-Purpose and Definition (Box-folder 9.13)
  - Youth Workers 1975 (Box-folder 9.14)
- Constitutions and By-Laws 1960-1977
  - By-Laws 1976 (Box-folder 10.1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws 1967 (Box-folder 10.2)
  - Handbook and By-Laws 1960 (Box-folder 10.3)
  - Handbook and Minutes 1976-1977 (Box-folder 10.4)
- Camps 1961-1968
  - Camp 1966-1967 (Box-folder 11.1)
  - Camp 1968 (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Camp 1971 (Box-folder 11.3)
  - Girl Scout Camp 1967 (Box-folder 11.5)
  - Summer Camp 1961-1962 (Box-folder 11.6)
- Committees and Programs 1959-1981
  - Action Project Material (Box-folder 12.1)
  - Adult Learning Center-Advisory Committee 1980 (Box-folder 12.2)
  - Big Sister Program 1967 (Box-folder 12.3)
  - Big Sister Program-Y Teens 1967 (Box-folder 12.4)
  - Building Committee 1972-1973 (Box-folder 12.5)
  - Capital Area Agency on Aging 1979-1980 (Box-folder 12.6)
  - CETA Recreation Project 1978 (Box-folder 12.7)
  - Collegiate School Buddy Program 1968 (Box-folder 12.8)
  - Committee on Annual Awards (1 of 2) (Box-folder 12.9)
  - Committee on Annual Awards (2 of 2) (Box-folder 12.10)
  - Cosmopolitan Club 1979 (Box-folder 12.11)
  - Council 1971 (Box-folder 12.12)
  - Delinquency Prevention and Youth Development Program 1974-1977 (Box-folder 12.13)
  - Drop-Out Work Program-Westwood 1963 (Box-folder 12.14)
  - Drug Program 1974 (Box-folder 12.15)
  - Educational Community Study 1963 (Box-folder 12.16)
  - Educational Development and Guidance Program 1979 (Box-folder 12.17)
  - Educational Development and Guidance Program-Advisory Committee 1979 (Box-folder 12.18)
  - Educational Development and Guidance Program-Budget and Forms 1981 (Box-folder 12.19)
  - Educational Development and Guidance Program-Reports 1978 (Box-folder 12.20)
  - Educational Development and Guidance Program-3rd Year Proposal 1980 (Box-folder 12.21)
  - Energy Emergency Employment Project 1977 (Box-folder 12.22)
  - Fall Program 1962 (Box-folder 12.23)
  - Field Service Organization 1978 (Box-folder 12.24)
  - Food Program-USDA 1976 (Box-folder 12.25)
  - Food Program-USDA 1978 (Box-folder 12.26)
  - Food Program-USDA Reports 1976 (Box-folder 12.27)
  - Food Program-USDA Reports 1977 (Box-folder 12.28)
  - Food Program-USDA Reports 1978 (Box-folder 12.29)
  - General Information on Organization 1962 (Box-folder 13.1)
  - General Materials on Organization (Box-folder 13.2)
  - Health Program 1971 (Box-folder 13.3)
  - Hot-Teen Employment Program (Box-folder 13.4)
  - Joint Agency Planning Committee 1973 (Box-folder 13.5)
  - Kiwanis Inventory Club-Gifts 1971 (Box-folder 13.6)
  - Kiwanis Projects 1965 (Box-folder 13.7)
  - Kiwanis Projects 1966 (Box-folder 13.8)
  - Kiwanis Projects 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13.9)
  - Lunch Program 1976 (Box-folder 13.10)
  - Lunch Program 1977 (Box-folder 13.11)
  - Main to the James Development Committee 1972 (Box-folder 13.12)
  - Model City's Project 1967 (Box-folder 13.13)
  - National Tenants Organization 1972 (Box-folder 13.14)
  - National Young Project 1974 (Box-folder 13.15)
  - National Youth Project Using Mini-Bikes 1975 (Box-folder 13.16)
  - Nominating Committee 1975 (Box-folder 13.17)
  - Nutrition Program 1975 (Box-folder 13.18)
  - Personnel Committee 1974 (Box-folder 13.19)
  - Personnel Committee 1978-1980 (Box-folder 13.20)
  - Police-Community Relations 1971 (Box-folder 13.21)
  - Pre-School Program 1981 (Box-folder 13.22)
  - Program Committee 1975 (Box-folder 13.23)
  - Programs (Box-folder 13.24)
  - Project COPE 1980 (Box-folder 13.25)
  - Richmond Community Action Program 1972 (Box-folder 13.26)
  - Save Our Homes Organization 1976 (Box-folder 13.27)
  - Save Our Homes Organization-Letters 1979 (Box-folder 13.28)
  - Staff and Program Committee Meetings (Box-folder 13.29)
  - Summer Programs 1959 (Box-folder 13.30)
  - Summer Programs 1973 (Box-folder 13.31)
  - Summer Programs 1980 (Box-folder 13.32)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program 1978 (Box-folder 13.33)
  - Teen Drama Club 1963 (Box-folder 13.34)
  - The Advocate-Richmond Community Action Program Newsletter 1973 (Box-folder 13.35)
  - The Buddy Club 1966-1969 (Box-folder 13.36)
  - USDA Food Program 1979-1980 (Box-folder 14.1)
  - Volunteer Program 1975 (Box-folder 14.2)
  - Volunteer Program 1979 (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Women's Legislative Committee 1981 (Box-folder 14.4)
  - Youth Summer Program (Box-folder 14.5)
  - Young Employee Program-Advisory Committee 1981 (Box-folder 14.6)
  - Youth 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14.7)
  - Youth Employment Project Advisory Board 1981 (Box-folder 14.8)
  - Youth Employment Project-Close Out 1981 (Box-folder 14.9)
  - Youth Employment Project Correspondence-Other Agencies 1981 (Box-folder 14.10)
  - Youth Employment Project-Finances 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14.11)
  - Youth Employment Project-Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box-folder 14.12)
  - Youth Employment Project-Miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box-folder 14.13)
  - Youth Employment Project-Organization Grants (Box-folder 14.14)
  - Youth Employment Project-Program Description and Objectives (Box-folder 14.15)
  - Youth Employment Project-Reporting Instructions 1981 (Box-folder 14.16)
- Oregon Hill Project 1954-1979
  - A Community Profile of Oregon Hill 1975 (Box-folder 15.1)
  - A Community Study of Oregon Hill 1976 (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Clippings of Programs and Oregon Hill (Box-folder 15.3)
  - Historical Oregon Hill 1975 (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Inter-Agency Services Council-Oregon Hill 1979 (Box-folder 15.5)
  - Master Plan-Oregon Hill Neighborhood (Box-folder 15.6)
  - Oregon Hill Baptist Center 1977 (Box-folder 15.7)
  - Oregon Hill Civic Association 1973 (Box-folder 15.8)